### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/shrikant-singh-9504402 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Data Analysis Business Analysis Analytics

## Languages

English Hindi

## Honors-Awards

Amazon Cowboy Award
MIT Summer research Scholarship
ISB Merit based Scholarship
BHP Billiton Summer Research
Scholarship
Karlruhe University Research
Scholarship

#### **Publications**

Exploring carbon nanotubes as catalysts in Hydrogen Fuel Cells

# **Shrikant Singh**

Retail | Amazon | ISB | IIT Bengaluru

# Summary

I currently serve as Category Head- PC Business at Appario Retail and as Program Head for Appario's B2B business across Mobiles, Electonics and PC businesses. Appario Retail is a seller on Amazon India and is wholly owned subsidiary of a JV between Amazon and the Patni group.

I joined Amazon India in May'14 & was involved in several new launches on Amazon.in - Pets Supplies in Aug'14, Grocery in Oct'14, Amazon NOW in Mar'15, Amazon Pantry in May'15 and Prime NOW in June'17.

In Jan'18, I moved to my current role at Appario.

Pre Amazon and MBA, I spent 3.5 years with Mu Sigma working on data analytics projects for Fortune 500 clients out of our Bangalore and US offices.

# Experience

Appario Retail Private Limited 2 years 8 months

Manager, Vendor Management - Personal Computers July 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months) Bengaluru Area, India

Business Head at Appario Retail - Currently leading customer shopping experience & internal PnL management for PC Peripherals portfolio on

- Amazon India : 1. Printers & Ink
- 2. Storage devices
- 3. Laptop & Tablet Accessories
- 4. PC Gaming
- Networking devices
- 6. Desktop and Laptop Components

I am additionally responsible for launching and scaling Appario Retail operations for all categories on Amazon's business (B2B) platform :

- 1. Personal Computers & PC Peripherals
- 2. Consumer Electronics ( Audio and Cameras)
- 3. Mobiles & Mobile accessories
- 4. Office Products
- 5. Musical Instruments

Senior Vendor Manager -Personal Computers January 2018 - June 2018 (6 months) Bangalore

Part of the launch and scale up team at Appario Retail.

Responsibilities: To launch and manage the PnLs for categories:

- 1. Storage
- 2. Gaming
- 3. PC Components
- 4. IT Accessories.

#### Amazon India

3 years 8 months

Senior Category Manager - Grocery, Pets Supplies & Prime NOW April 2016 - December 2017 (1 year 9 months)

Bangalore

- 1. As part of the International Expansion team at Amazon, I am responsible for managing customer focused inputs (selection, instock and pricing) along with the P&L ownership for Grocery and Pets Supplies categories.
- 2. Also involved in new initiatives and launches under the Grocery umbrella:
- a. Amazon Pantry in Bangalore
- b. Amazon NOW in all metros
- 3. I am also responsible for handling special Supply Chain and Ops projects for intrinsically transit sensitive categories such as Grocery, Beauty, Household Supplies, Baby and Pets

Instock Manager - Grocery and Pets Supplies May 2014 - March 2016 (1 year 11 months) Bengaluru Area, India

1. Launched India's largest online/offline Pets Supplies category, where I was responsible for brand engagement, inventory management, vendor

management and seller management functions for a category with 6X selection of its closest competition

- 2. Launched India's largest online/offline Grocery and Gourmet Foods on Amazon India. Led inventory management and seller management functions for the category, which currently is operating with over 300,000 SKUs
- 3. Member of Launch team for Amazon Now Pilot (Kirana Now) in Bangalore

## Mu Sigma

Associate Manager - Analytics Consulting November 2009 - April 2013 (3 years 6 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

As a data scientist, my responsibility was to engage with clients, understand their business objectives, analyze their business data and present structured data driven solutions to the business problems.

Some of the prominent problem statements that I helped solve were:

- 1. Building CRM dashboards for large B2B retailer
- 2. Designing Attrition models for one of the largest B2C home improvement supplies retailer
- 3. Designing new store layouts for the largest B2C retailer in US
- 4. Piloted a new customer retention program for one of Spain's largest banks

### GE

Consultant, GE Plastics June 2009 - November 2009 (6 months) Bangalore

As a Consultant, my function was to collaborate with GE R&D scientists and test out new eco-friendly polymers.

# Education

Indian School of Business

Post Graduate Program (PGP), Operations & Marketing (2013 - 2014)

Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur Integrated MS, Industrial Chemistry (2004 - 2009)